{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354902.573689, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.5736902, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf023a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf03fc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf04c4-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What is a novel coronavirus?", "answerText": "A novel coronavirus is a new coronavirus that has not been previously identified. The virus causing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), is not the same as the coronaviruses that commonly circulate among humans and cause mild illness, like the common cold.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354902.654119, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.65412, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf05d2-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf0690-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf0744-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What is coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)?", "answerText": "Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is a respiratory illness that can spread from person to person. There are many types of human coronaviruses, including some that commonly cause mild upper-respiratory tract illnesses. COVID-19 is a new disease, caused by a novel (or new) coronavirus that has not previously been seen in humans. Current symptoms reported for patients with COVID-19 have included mild to severe respiratory illness with fever, cough, and difficulty breathing.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354902.700471, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.700472, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf0816-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf08ca-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf0974-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Can people in the U.S. get COVID-19?", "answerText": "Yes. There have been cases of COVID-19 in the U.S. related to international travel, person-to-person spread, and reported community spread in parts of the United States. This is a rapidly evolving situation and CDC updates the risk assessment as needed", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354903.3893929, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354903.3893938, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf0a6e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf0b22-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf0bcc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "How can I prevent COVID-19?", "answerText": "The best way to prevent illness is to avoid being exposed to the virus. CDC recommends everyday preventive actions to help prevent the spread of respiratory diseases, including:\nAvoid close contact with people who are sick.\nAvoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth.\nStay home when you are sick.\nCover your cough or sneeze with a tissue, then throw the tissue in the trash.\nFollow CDC’s recommendations for using a facemask.\n\tCDC does not recommend that people who are well wear a facemask to protect themselves from respiratory diseases, including COVID-19.\nFacemasks should be used by people who show symptoms of COVID-19 to help prevent the spread of the disease to others. The use of facemasks is also crucial for health workers and people who are taking care of someone in close settings (at home or in a health care facility).\n\nWash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after going to the bathroom; before eating; and after blowing your nose, coughing, or sneezing. If soap and water are not readily available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol. Always wash hands with soap and water if hands are visibly dirty. For information about handwashing, see CDC’s Handwashing website.\nClean and disinfect frequently touched objects and surfaces using a regular household cleaning spray or wipe.\n\tUse disinfectants appropriate for the surface. Most common EPA-registered household disinfectants will work. Follow the manufacturer’s instructions for all cleaning and disinfection products (e.g., concentration, application method and contact time, etc.).\n\nView the current list of products that meet EPA’s criteria for use against SARS-CoV-2, the cause of COVID-19. \n\n\nTo use household bleach to disinfect surfaces, mix: \n\n5 tablespoons (1/3rd cup) bleach per gallon of water.\n\t\t\tOR\n\n\n4 teaspoons bleach per quart of water Follow manufacturer’s instructions for application and proper ventilation. Check to ensure the product is not past its expiration date. Never mix household bleach with ammonia or any other cleanser. Unexpired household bleach will be effective against coronaviruses when properly diluted.\n\n\n\nUse an alcohol solution with at least 70% alcohol.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354903.4793348, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354903.479336, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf0ca8-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf0d5c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf0e06-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What treatments are available for COVID-19?", "answerText": "People with COVID-19 should receive supportive care to help relieve symptoms. For people with laboratory confirmed COVID-19, illnesses have ranged from mild symptoms to severe illness and death. For severe illness, treatment should include care to support vital organ functions. Seek prompt medical attention if your illness gets worse (for example, you have difficulty breathing). Before seeking medical attention, call your health care provider and tell them that you have, or are being evaluated for, COVID-19. Put on a facemask before you enter the doctor’s office, clinic, or hospital.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354903.6800919, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354903.680094, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf0ee2-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf0f96-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf1040-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Can disinfectant sprays or wipes be used on my skin to prevent spread of COVID-19?", "answerText": "No. Always follow the instructions on household cleaners. Do not use disinfect sprays or wipes on your skin because it may cause skin and eye irritation. Disinfectant sprays or wipes are not intended for use on humans or animals. Disinfectant sprays or wipes are intended for use on hard, non-porous surfaces.\nView the current list of products that meet EPA’s criteria for use against SARS-CoV-2, the cause of COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354904.268516, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354904.268517, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf1108-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf11bc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf1266-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Products online claim to prevent COVID-19. Where can I report websites selling fraudulent medical products?", "answerText": "You can report websites selling fraudulent medical products to the FDA through our website, by phone, or mail. Learn more...", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354904.942842, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354904.942842, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf137e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf1446-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf14f0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Are there any vaccines or other medical products to prevent COVID-19?", "answerText": "At this time there is no vaccine to prevent coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). The FDA is working with vaccine developers and other researchers and manufacturers to help expedite the development and availability of medical products such as vaccines, antibodies, and drugs to prevent COVID-19. Read more about what FDA is doing to mitigate the effects of COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354905.0645728, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354905.064574, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf15b8-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf166c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf1716-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Are antibiotics effective in preventing or treating COVID-19?", "answerText": "No. Antibiotics do not work against viruses; they only work on bacterial infections. Antibiotics do not prevent or treat coronavirus disease (COVID-19), because COVID-19 is caused by a virus, not bacteria.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354905.177294, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354905.1772952, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf17de-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "9bc62e88-7085-11ea-8582-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "adaf196e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What is a biological medical product or a biologic?", "answerText": "Biological products include a wide range of products such as vaccines , blood and blood components , allergenics , somatic cells , gene therapy , tissues , and recombinant therapeutic proteins . Biologics can be composed of sugars , proteins , or nucleic acids or complex combinations of these substances , or may be living entities such as cells and tissues .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354905.3868392, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354905.386841, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf1a40-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf1af4-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf1b9e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "How can a person or company with a potential biologic for COVID-19 work with the FDA?", "answerText": "The FDA’s Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research (CBER) encourages all potential sponsors/product developers to initiate contact as early as possible so that they will have the opportunity to consider our recommendations in planning preclinical/pre-investigational and clinical development programs for biological products that are intended to prevent, mitigate, treat or cure COVID-19.\nSponsors wishing to develop a biological product, including vaccine developers, can email industry.biologics@fda.hhs.gov or call 1-800-835-4709 for further information.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354905.5264819, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354905.526483, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf1c66-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf1d1a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf1dba-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Does COVID-19 present a risk to the safety of the nation’s blood supply?", "answerText": "In general, respiratory viruses are not known to be transmitted by blood transfusion, and there have been no reported cases of transfusion-transmitted coronavirus.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354905.695992, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354905.6959932, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf1e82-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf1f36-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf1fd6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Can SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19, be transmitted by blood transfusion?", "answerText": "In general, respiratory viruses are not known to be transmitted by blood transfusion, and there have been no reported cases of transfusion-transmitted coronavirus.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354905.941261, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354905.941262, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf20a8-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf2152-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf21fc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What steps are being taken to protect the U.S. blood supply from SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19?", "answerText": "Blood donors must be healthy and feel well on the day of donation. Routine blood donor screening measures that are already in place should prevent individuals with respiratory infections from donating blood. For example, blood donors must be in good health and have a normal temperature on the day of donation.\nDonors are instructed to contact the donor center if they become ill after donation, so that their blood or plasma will not be used. Even when a donor develops COVID-19 after donation, however, there have been no cases of COVID-19 linked to donor blood or products made from blood.   \nFDA has provided additional information to blood establishments on its website.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354906.101983, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354906.101985, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf22c4-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf236e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf2418-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Why aren’t blood centers testing donors for SARS-CoV-2?", "answerText": "At this time, the FDA does not recommend using laboratory tests to screen blood. Someone who has symptoms of COVID-19, including fever, cough, and shortness of breath, is not healthy enough to donate blood. Standard screening processes already in place will mean that someone with these symptoms will not be allowed to donate.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354906.302648, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354906.30266, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf24ea-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf2594-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf263e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is it safe for me to donate blood during the coronavirus pandemic?", "answerText": "If you are healthy and interested in donating blood, the FDA encourages you to contact a local donation center to make an appointment. One way to make a difference during a public health emergency is to donate blood if you are able. \nAABB: www.aabb.org; +1.301.907.6977\nAmerica’s Blood Centers: www.americasblood.org\nAmerican Red Cross: www.redcrossblood.org; +1.800.RED CROSS (+1.800.733.2767)\nArmed Services Blood Program: www.militaryblood.dod.mil; +1.703.681.8024", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354906.592888, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354906.59289, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf2706-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf27b0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf285a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is the FDA recommending that blood and plasma establishments implement screening measures for the deferral of whole blood and plasma donors who may be at risk of having COVID-19?", "answerText": "Precautionary donor education and/or deferral measures that blood establishments may wish to consider in response to the COVID-19 outbreak are available on FDA’s website. \nBased on the limited information available at this time, we suggest individuals refrain from donating blood at least 28 days after resolution of symptoms after a diagnosis of COVID-19 or 28 days after the date of departure from an outbreak area or the last possible close contact exposure to a person with COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354906.821504, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354906.821505, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf292c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf29d6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf2a80-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Can COVID-19 be transmitted through human cells, tissues, or cellular and tissue-based products (HCT/Ps)?", "answerText": "Respiratory viruses, in general, are not known to be transmitted by implantation, transplantation, infusion, or transfer of human cells, tissues, or cellular or tissue-based products (HCT/Ps). The potential for transmission of COVID-19 by HCT/Ps is unknown at this time. There have been no reported cases of transmission of COVID-19 via HCT/Ps.\nRoutine screening measures are already in place for evaluating clinical evidence of infection in HCT/P donors. Read more…", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354907.0790331, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354907.0790348, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf2b52-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf2bfc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf2ca6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is the FDA recommending that establishments implement screening measures for the deferral of HCT/P donors of who may be at risk of having COVID-19?", "answerText": "The HCT/P establishment’s responsible person must evaluate a prospective donor and determine eligibility (21 CFR 1271.50). Based on the limited information available at this time, establishments may wish to consider the following donor history in the 28 days prior to HCT/P recovery for persons who have:\ntraveled to areas with COVID-19 outbreaks, as defined by CDC\nlived with individuals diagnosed with or suspected of having COVID-19 \nbeen diagnosed with or suspected of having COVID-19", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354907.23957, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354907.2395709, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf2d78-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf2e2c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf2ee0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Are there any FDA-approved drug products or medicines to treat COVID-19?", "answerText": "At this time, there are no FDA-approved drug products to treat COVID-19. The FDA is working with drug manufacturers and investigational new drug sponsors to expedite the development and availability of COVID-19 treatments. Read more about FDA’s actions to address the novel coronavirus with medical countermeasures.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354907.410582, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354907.410584, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf2fbc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf3070-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf311a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Who should a company contact about developing a treatment for COVID-19?", "answerText": "A company who wants to contact the FDA about a potential treatment for COVID-19 is encouraged to review COVID-19 Therapeutics: General Information for Interested Stakeholders for more information on submitting drug development proposals for review. \nThe Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA), a component of the HHS Assistant Secretary of Preparedness and Response (ASPR), is supporting U.S. government market research to identify medical countermeasures with the potential to help address the COVID-19 outbreak. If your company is developing therapeutics, vaccines, or other products, submit your ideas to BARDA's online portal.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354907.5581172, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354907.5581179, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf31e2-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf328c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf3336-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Q. Will Miracle Mineral Solution (MMS) cure COVID-19?", "answerText": "No. Miracle Mineral Solution does not cure COVID-19 and has not been approved by the FDA for any use. The solution, when mixed, develops into a dangerous bleach which has caused serious and potentially life-threatening side effects. For more information, see: FDA warns consumers about the dangerous and potentially life threatening side effects of Miracle Mineral Solution and Danger: Don’t Drink Miracle Mineral Solution or Similar Products.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354907.758202, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354907.7582028, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf33fe-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf34d0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf3584-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What is the FDA doing to protect people from fraudulent COVID-19 medical products?", "answerText": "We have established a cross-agency task force dedicated to closely monitoring for fraudulent COVID-19 products and claims. We have reached out to major retailers to ask for their help in monitoring online marketplaces for fraudulent COVID-19 products. Products sold are subject to FDA investigation and potential enforcement action if they claim to prevent, treat, or cure COVID-19 and have not demonstrated safety and effectiveness for that intended use. The task force has already worked with retailers to remove more than a dozen of these types of product listings online. \nOn March 6, 2020, the FDA and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) issued warning letters to seven companies for selling unapproved drugs that pose significant risks to patient health and violate federal law by making unapproved claims to treat COVID-19. View the warning letters for more information.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354907.984477, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354907.984478, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf364c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf3700-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf37a0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Are there going to be drug shortages due to drug manufacturer facility closures in China?", "answerText": "The FDA has been closely monitoring the supply chain with the expectation that the COVID-19 outbreak would likely impact the medical product supply chain, including potential disruptions to supply or shortages of critical medical products in the U.S. \nWe have been reaching out to manufacturers as part of our approach to identifying potential disruptions or shortages. We will use all available tools to react swiftly and mitigate the impact to U.S. patients and health care professionals when a potential disruption or shortage is identified.\nFind real-time information about drug shortages.\nLearn more in our drug shortages frequently asked questions.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.111291, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.111292, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf3868-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf391c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf39c6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Am I at risk for COVID-19 from taking FDA-approved drugs made in China?", "answerText": "Currently, there is no evidence to support transmission of COVID-19 associated with imported goods, including food and drugs for humans and pets. There have not been any cases of COVID-19 in the United States associated with imported goods.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.221382, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.221384, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf3a8e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf3b38-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf3be2-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Who should I contact with drug-related questions?", "answerText": "If you have additional questions, call FDA’s Division of Drug Information at (855) 543-3784 or email us at druginfo@fda.hhs.gov.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.31641, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.316415, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf3caa-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf3d86-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf3e30-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is there a test for COVID-19?", "answerText": "During public health emergencies declared under section 564 of the FD&C Act, the FDA is able to issue an Emergency Use Authorizations (EUAs) when certain criteria are met that allows for the use and distribution of potentially life-saving medical products to diagnose, treat, or prevent the disease, which can include diagnostic tests. Accordingly, the FDA has issued EUAs authorizing the use of diagnostic tests to detect the virus, called SARS-CoV-2, that causes COVID-19. \nThe FDA has also issued new policies and guidance to achieve more rapid testing capacity in the U.S.\nBecause the virus that causes COVID-19 is new, currently there is no FDA-approved or cleared test to diagnose or detect COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.469358, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.4693592, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf3f02-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf3fac-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf4056-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Are there any tests that I can purchase to test myself at home for COVID-19?", "answerText": "At this time, the FDA has not authorized any test that is available to purchase for testing yourself at home for COVID-19. The FDA sees the public health value in expanding the availability of COVID-19 testing through safe and accurate tests that may include home collection, and we are actively working with test developers in this space. You can find listings of tests that have received an EUA authorization as well as labs and manufacturers that have notified FDA as set forth in the FDA's Policy for Diagnostic Tests for Coronavirus Disease-2019.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.585597, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.585598, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf411e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf41d2-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf4272-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "When will other diagnostic tests for COVID-19 be authorized?", "answerText": "More than 100 companies have requested and received the FDA-developed EUA template for diagnostics for this outbreak. This template will help to expedite the development and authorization of other diagnostic products under EUAs. The templates for these diagnostic testing EUA submissions are now available on our website. If you need additional information, please refer to the FAQs on Diagnostic Testing for SARS-CoV-2.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.8086321, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.808633, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf433a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf43ee-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf448e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Should I purchase personal protective equipment such as facemasks or N95 respirators for me and my family?", "answerText": "CDC does not recommend that people who are well wear a facemask to protect themselves from respiratory illnesses, including COVID-19. Patients with confirmed or suspected COVID-19 should wear a facemask until they are isolated in a hospital or at home. The patient does not need to wear a facemask while isolated. The use of facemasks is also crucial for health workers and other people who are taking care of someone infected with COVID-19 in close settings (at home or in a health care facility).\nCDC does not recommend the routine use of respirators, such as N95 respirators. Not everyone is able to wear a respirator due to medical conditions that may be made worse when breathing through a respirator.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354908.948241, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354908.948242, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf457e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf463c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf46dc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "What is the difference between a facemask and an N95 respirator?", "answerText": "See CDC’s infographic: Understanding the Difference: Surgical Masks and N95 Respirators. More information on personal protective equipment, including surgical masks (facemasks) and N95 respirators, is available on the FDA’s website.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354909.318909, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354909.318913, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf47b8-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf4862-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf490c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is there a shortage of personal protective equipment (PPE) such as gloves, masks, and N95 respirators?", "answerText": "The FDA is not currently aware of specific widespread shortages of personal protective equipment, but there are reports of increased ordering of these products and shortages have been observed in some U.S. health care institutions. We have received information from healthcare organizations that some distributors may have placed certain types of PPE on allocation, basing the quantity available to the healthcare facility on previous usage, not projected use. Increased use may exceed the available supply of PPE, resulting in shortages at some healthcare organizations.\nThe FDA and CDC are aware that as the COVID-19 outbreak continues to expand globally, the supply chain for these devices will continue to be substantially stressed as demand exceeds available supplies. Under the circumstances of this emergency, nationwide shortages are anticipated. \nThe FDA and CDC took action to make more respirators, including certain N95s, available to health care personnel for use in health care settings. Issuing an Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) is intended to maximize the number of respirators available for health care personnel during the COVID-19 outbreak.  \nAs with prior public health emergencies, the FDA is in contact with medical device manufacturers and others in the supply chain, including hospitals and group purchasing organizations. If a potential shortage or disruption of medical products is identified by the FDA, we will use all available tools to react swiftly and mitigate the impact to U.S. patients and health care professionals. \nThe FDA encourages manufacturers and healthcare facilities to report any supply disruptions to the device shortages mailbox at deviceshortages@fda.hhs.gov.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354909.4455712, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354909.4455721, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf49de-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf4a88-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf4b32-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Do the N95 respirators that are NIOSH-approved for industrial settings and other workplaces like construction sites, but do not comply with the FDA’s regulatory authority to meet the needs of the U.S. healthcare system, still offer adequate protection?", "answerText": "The FDA determined that certain respirators approved by NIOSH and authorized by FDA under the EUA may be effective in preventing health care personnel from airborne particulate exposure, including exposure to the virus that causes COVID-19. Given the increased demand and supply challenges on the availability of respirators, at the CDC’s request, the FDA granted an EUA to CDC that helps to provide additional respirators to enable more healthcare personnel in healthcare settings to have access to this potentially lifesaving personal protective equipment.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354909.576546, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354909.5765471, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf4bfa-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf4ccc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf4d80-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Who makes the “standard” or NIOSH-approved N95 respirators?", "answerText": "Please see the CDC website for a list of  NIOSH-approved N95 respirators.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354909.6846762, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354909.6846771, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf4e52-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf4efc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf4fa6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Do N95 respirators provide protection from coronavirus?", "answerText": "N95 respirators and other personal protective equipment (PPE) such as gloves and surgical gowns are designed to create a non-disease specific barrier to penetration of substances, solids, liquids, or airborne particles.  In general, neither FDA nor the manufacturer can provide assurances that PPE will protect you against a specific disease. If performance data has met FDA requirements and demonstrate protection against a specific disease, the product labeling generally will state the claim for protection against a specific virus or bacteria. See FDA’s Questions About Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) web page for more information.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354909.771917, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354909.771919, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf506e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5118-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf51b8-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Do expired N95 respirators still offer protection?", "answerText": "Please refer to CDC Release of Stockpiled N95 Filtering Facepiece Respirators Beyond the Manufacturer-Designated Shelf Life for more information.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354909.9809148, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354909.980916, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf528a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5334-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf53d4-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Who should I contact if I have questions about medical devices or need more information?", "answerText": "Please contact the FDA’s Center for Devices and Radiological Health (CDRH)’s Division of Industry and Consumer Education (DICE) for general questions and information.\nIf you need additional information completing the diagnostic EUA template or wish to consider use of an alternative specimen type, please contact the Division of Microbiology Devices at (301) 348-1778 or email CDRH-EUA-Templates@fda.hhs.gov.\nIf you have questions about the EUA for personal respiratory protective devices, including N95 respirators, please email CDRH-NonDiagnosticEUA-Templates@fda.hhs.gov.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.030302, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.030304, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf54b0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5564-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf5636-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Will there be food shortages?", "answerText": "There are no nationwide shortages of food, although in some cases the inventory of certain foods at your grocery store might be temporarily low before stores can restock. Food production and manufacturing are widely dispersed throughout the U.S. and there are currently no wide-spread disruptions reported in the supply chain. \nFDA is closely monitoring the food supply chain for any shortages in collaboration with industry and our federal and state partners. We are in regular contact with food manufacturers and grocery stores.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.28233, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.282332, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf56fe-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5816-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf58d4-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is food imported to the United States from China and other countries affected by coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), at risk of spreading COVID-19?", "answerText": "Currently, there is no evidence to support transmission of COVID-19 associated with imported goods and there are no reported cases of COVID-19 in the United States associated with imported goods.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.4182231, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.418224, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf599c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5a50-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf5b04-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Are food products produced in the United States a risk for the spread of COVID-19?", "answerText": "There is no evidence to suggest that food produced in the United States can transmit COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.606962, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.606963, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf5bd6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5c8a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf5d2a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Can I get sick with COVID-19 from touching food, the food packaging, or food contact surfaces, if the coronavirus was present on it?", "answerText": "Currently there is no evidence of food or food packaging being associated with transmission of COVID-19.  Like other viruses, it is possible that the virus that causes COVID-19 can survive on surfaces or objects. For that reason, it is critical to follow the 4 key steps of food safety—clean, separate, cook, and chill.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.678079, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.678081, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf5e06-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf5eb0-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf5f5a-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Is the U.S. food supply safe?", "answerText": "Currently there is no evidence of food or food packaging being associated with transmission of COVID-19.   \nUnlike foodborne gastrointestinal (GI) viruses like norovirus and hepatitis A that often make people ill through contaminated food, SARS-CoV-2, which causes COVID-19, is a virus that causes respiratory illness and not gastrointestinal illness, and foodborne exposure to this virus is not known to be a route of transmission.\nIt may be possible that a person can get COVID-19 by touching a surface or object that has the virus on it and then touching their own mouth, nose, or possibly their eyes, but this is not thought to be the main way the virus spreads. That’s why it’s always critical to follow the 4 key steps of food safety—clean, separate, cook, and chill.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.76859, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.7685912, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf6022-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf60d6-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf6176-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Can I get COVID-19 from a food worker handling my food?", "answerText": "Currently, there is no evidence of food or food packaging being associated with transmission of COVID-19. However, the virus that causes COVID-19 is spreading from person-to-person in some communities in the U.S. The CDC recommends that if you are sick, stay home until you are better and no longer pose a risk of infecting others. \nAnyone handling, preparing and serving food should always follow safe food handling procedures, such as washing hands and surfaces often.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354910.8679879, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354910.867989, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf623e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf62f2-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf639c-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Should food workers who are ill stay home?", "answerText": "CDC recommends that employees who have symptoms of acute respiratory illness stay home and not come to work until they are free of fever (100.4° F [37.8° C] or greater using an oral thermometer), signs of a fever, and any other symptoms for at least 24 hours, without the use of fever-reducing or other symptom-altering medicines (e.g. cough suppressants). Employees should notify their supervisor and stay home if they are sick. We recommend that businesses review CDC’s interim guidance for businesses and employers for planning and responding to coronavirus disease.  Also see the FDA’s Retail Food Protection: Employee Health and Personal Hygiene Handbook.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354911.2562408, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354911.256242, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf646e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf6522-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf65cc-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Should food facilities (grocery stores, manufacturing facilities, restaurants, etc.) perform any special cleaning or sanitation procedures for COVID-19?", "answerText": "CDC recommends routine cleaning of all frequently touched surfaces in the workplace, such as workstations, countertops, and doorknobs. Use the cleaning agents that are usually used in these areas and follow the directions on the label. CDC does not recommend any additional disinfection beyond routine cleaning at this time. \nView the EPA-registered disinfectant products on the Disinfectants for Use Against SARS-CoV-2 list that have qualified under EPA's emerging viral pathogen program for use against SARS-CoV-2, the coronavirus that causes COVID-19. \nRestaurants and retail food establishments are regulated at the state and local level. State, local, and tribal regulators use the Food Code published by the FDA to develop or update their own food safety rules. Generally, FDA-regulated food manufacturers are required to maintain clean facilities, including, as appropriate, clean and sanitized food contact surfaces, and to have food safety plans in place.   Food safety plans include a hazards analysis and risk-based preventive controls and include procedures for maintaining clean and sanitized facilities and food contact surfaces. See: FSMA Final Rule for Preventive Controls for Human Food.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585354911.488988, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354911.4889889, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "adaf669e-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "answerUUID": "adaf6748-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "exampleUUID": "adaf67e8-6d17-11ea-8da9-c81f66e17f9e", "questionText": "Since restaurant workers and other service industry employees have ongoing contact with the public, are there any special precautions these workers should take to avoid becoming sick with a respiratory illness, such as wearing masks?", "answerText": "CDC does not recommend that people who are well wear a facemask to protect themselves from respiratory diseases, including COVID-19. Facemasks should be used by people who show symptoms of COVID-19 to help prevent the spread of the disease to others. The use of facemasks is also crucial for health workers and people who are taking care of someone with COVID-19 in close settings (at home or in a health care facility).\nCDC recommends everyday preventive actions for everyone, including service industry workers and customers:\nAvoid close contact with people who are sick.\nAvoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth.\nStay home when you are sick.\nCover your cough or sneeze with a tissue, then throw the tissue in the trash.\nWash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after going to the bathroom; before eating; and after blowing your nose, coughing, or sneezing.\n\tIf soap and water are not readily available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol. Always wash hands with soap and water if hands are visibly dirty.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.4636219, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc622d0-7085-11ea-b327-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc62348-7085-11ea-a2ff-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc623a2-7085-11ea-b3b5-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. Where can I buy hand sanitizer ? If I ca n’t find it in the store , can I make my own ?", "answerText": "A. Many retail stores and pharmacies sell hand sanitizers . However , we understand that many stores have run out of hand sanitizers and they may be difficult to find . To help increase the availability of hand sanitizers , the FDA has issued guidance for the temporary preparation of alcohol - based hand sanitizers by some companies and pharmacies during the public health emergency posed by COVID-19 .  \n  The FDA does not recommend that consumers make their own hand sanitizer . If made incorrectly , hand sanitizer can be ineffective , and there have been reports of skin burns from homemade hand sanitizer . The agency lacks verifiable information on the methods being used to prepare hand sanitizer at home and whether they are safe for use on human skin . \n  See the Q&A for Consumers : Hand Sanitizers and COVID-19 for more information .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. Where can I buy hand sanitizer ? If I ca n’t find it in the store , can I make my own ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. Many retail stores and pharmacies sell hand sanitizers . However , we understand that many stores have run out of hand sanitizers and they may be difficult to find . To help increase the availability of hand sanitizers , the FDA has issued guidance for the temporary preparation of alcohol - based hand sanitizers by some companies and pharmacies during the public health emergency posed by COVID-19 .  \n The FDA does not recommend that consumers make their own hand sanitizer . If made incorrectly , hand sanitizer can be ineffective , and there have been reports of skin burns from homemade hand sanitizer . The agency lacks verifiable information on the methods being used to prepare hand sanitizer at home and whether they are safe for use on human skin . \n See the Q&A for Consumers : Hand Sanitizers and COVID-19 for more information .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.463658, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc62438-7085-11ea-894e-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc6249c-7085-11ea-a42b-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc624f6-7085-11ea-b3ec-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. What do I do if I get a rash or other reaction to hand sanitizer ?", "answerText": "A. Call your doctor if you experience a serious reaction to hand sanitizer . FDA encourages consumers and health care professionals to report adverse events experienced with the use of hand sanitizers to the FDA ’s MedWatch Adverse Event Reporting program : \n  Complete and submit the report online ; or \n  Download and complete the form , then submit it via fax at 1 - 800-FDA-0178 . \n  Include as much information as you can about the product that caused the reaction , including the product name , the manufacturer , and the lot number ( if available ) .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. What do I do if I get a rash or other reaction to hand sanitizer ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. Call your doctor if you experience a serious reaction to hand sanitizer . FDA encourages consumers and health care professionals to report adverse events experienced with the use of hand sanitizers to the FDA ’s MedWatch Adverse Event Reporting program : \n Complete and submit the report online ; or \n Download and complete the form , then submit it via fax at 1 - 800-FDA-0178 . \n Include as much information as you can about the product that caused the reaction , including the product name , the manufacturer , and the lot number ( if available ) .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.4637618, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc62848-7085-11ea-92d5-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc628b6-7085-11ea-aa10-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc62910-7085-11ea-8f31-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "How do I know if I ’ m an essential worker during the COVID-19 pandemic ?", "answerText": "Critical infrastructure industries , including many FDA - regulated industries such as food , drugs , and medical equipment , have a special responsibility in these times to continue operations . On March 19 , 2020 , the Department of Homeland Security ( DHS ) Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Agency ( CISA ) issued guidance on defining essential workers . This guidance offers an initial baseline for governments and industry to use when identifying key groups of employees during COVID-19 response . This guidance is not binding and serves as a starting point for local and state governments . View more frequently asked questions from CISA .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "How do I know if I ’m an essential worker during the COVID-19 pandemic ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Critical infrastructure industries , including many FDA - regulated industries such as food , drugs , and medical equipment , have a special responsibility in these times to continue operations . On March 19 , 2020 , the Department of Homeland Security ( DHS ) Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Agency ( CISA ) issued guidance on defining essential workers . This guidance offers an initial baseline for governments and industry to use when identifying key groups of employees during COVID-19 response . This guidance is not binding and serves as a starting point for local and state governments . View more frequently asked questions from CISA .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.463795, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc62988-7085-11ea-8231-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc629e2-7085-11ea-a373-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc62a3a-7085-11ea-b9e0-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Who should I contact with questions about essential employees or FDA - regulated products traveling through areas with curfews and restrictions because of the coronavirus ?", "answerText": "If you are experiencing issues with your supply chain , delivery of goods , or business continuity , please contact : CISA.CAT@cisa.dhs.gov .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Who should I contact with questions about essential employees or FDA - regulated products traveling through areas with curfews and restrictions because of the coronavirus ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "If you are experiencing issues with your supply chain , delivery of goods , or business continuity , please contact : CISA.CAT@cisa.dhs.gov .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465148, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc65e6c-7085-11ea-90be-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc65e9e-7085-11ea-96d2-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc65ec6-7085-11ea-a4db-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. Can animals get novel coronavirus disease ( COVID-19 ) ?", "answerText": "A. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention ( CDC ) , there is no scientific evidence indicating that any animals in the United States , including pets , can spread COVID-19 or that they might be a source of infection in the United States . To date , there have been no reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 . \n  The FDA is aware that more than one dog has tested positive for the virus that causes COVID-19 , based on information from the Hong Kong Agriculture , Fisheries & Conservation Department . There is no evidence that companion animals , including pets , can spread COVID-19 or that they might be a source of infection in the United States .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. Can animals get novel coronavirus disease ( COVID-19 ) ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention ( CDC ) , there is no scientific evidence indicating that any animals in the United States , including pets , can spread COVID-19 or that they might be a source of infection in the United States . To date , there have been no reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 . \n The FDA is aware that more than one dog has tested positive for the virus that causes COVID-19 , based on information from the Hong Kong Agriculture , Fisheries & Conservation Department . There is no evidence that companion animals , including pets , can spread COVID-19 or that they might be a source of infection in the United States .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465166, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc65f18-7085-11ea-8962-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc65f48-7085-11ea-89b0-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc65f70-7085-11ea-919c-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. If I have COVID-19 , can I infect my pet ? Can I get COVID-19 from my pet ?", "answerText": "A. There is currently no evidence that pets can spread COVID-19 or that they might be a source of infection in the United States . Although there have not been reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 , it is still recommended that people sick with COVID-19 limit contact with animals until more information is known about the new coronavirus . When possible , have another member of your household care for your animals while you are sick . If you are sick with COVID-19 , avoid contact with your pet , including petting , snuggling , being kissed or licked , and sharing food . If you must care for your pet or be around animals while you are sick , wash your hands before and after you interact with pets . Global health organizations are monitoring the outbreak ’s potential impact on animal health and will notify the public if new information becomes available .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. If I have COVID-19 , can I infect my pet ? Can I get COVID-19 from my pet ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. There is currently no evidence that pets can spread COVID-19 or that they might be a source of infection in the United States . Although there have not been reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 , it is still recommended that people sick with COVID-19 limit contact with animals until more information is known about the new coronavirus . When possible , have another member of your household care for your animals while you are sick . If you are sick with COVID-19 , avoid contact with your pet , including petting , snuggling , being kissed or licked , and sharing food . If you must care for your pet or be around animals while you are sick , wash your hands before and after you interact with pets . Global health organizations are monitoring the outbreak ’s potential impact on animal health and will notify the public if new information becomes available .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.4651809, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc65fac-7085-11ea-a5a8-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc65fde-7085-11ea-83fd-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc66006-7085-11ea-b895-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. What should I do if my pet or other animals seem ill and I think it might be COVID-19 ?", "answerText": "A. To date , there have not been any reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 in the United States . \n  If your animal appears to be ill , you should contact your veterinarian just like you would for any health concern . In order to ensure the veterinary clinic is prepared for your pet , you should call ahead and arrange the hospital or clinic visit . If you are sick with COVID-19 or suspect you might be sick with COVID-19 , a family member or friend from outside your household may bring the animal to a veterinary hospital or clinic . Regardless of who takes your pet to the veterinarian , follow the animal hospital ’s advice on proper safety precautions prior to arrival . Showing up to a veterinarian ’s office unannounced could put staff or other pet owners at risk , even if you are not showing symptoms or have resolving symptoms .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. What should I do if my pet or other animals seem ill and I think it might be COVID-19 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. To date , there have not been any reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 in the United States . \n If your animal appears to be ill , you should contact your veterinarian just like you would for any health concern . In order to ensure the veterinary clinic is prepared for your pet , you should call ahead and arrange the hospital or clinic visit . If you are sick with COVID-19 or suspect you might be sick with COVID-19 , a family member or friend from outside your household may bring the animal to a veterinary hospital or clinic . Regardless of who takes your pet to the veterinarian , follow the animal hospital ’s advice on proper safety precautions prior to arrival . Showing up to a veterinarian ’s office unannounced could put staff or other pet owners at risk , even if you are not showing symptoms or have resolving symptoms .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.4651961, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc66042-7085-11ea-9253-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc6607e-7085-11ea-8e9e-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc660b0-7085-11ea-a311-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. If my pet has been exposed to someone who has COVID-19 , do they need to be quarantined ? If so , for how long ?", "answerText": "A. Although there is no evidence that pets can get sick from COVID-19 or spread the virus that causes COVID-19 , you may wish to quarantine your pet for the same amount of time as people are being asked to quarantine – 14 days .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. If my pet has been exposed to someone who has COVID-19 , do they need to be quarantined ? If so , for how long ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. Although there is no evidence that pets can get sick from COVID-19 or spread the virus that causes COVID-19 , you may wish to quarantine your pet for the same amount of time as people are being asked to quarantine – 14 days .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465214, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc660f6-7085-11ea-9e47-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc66146-7085-11ea-9a94-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc6619e-7085-11ea-be86-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. Are there any approved products that can prevent or treat COVID-19 in animals ?", "answerText": "A. No . Under the Federal Food , Drug , and Cosmetic ( FD&C ) Act , “ articles intended for use in the diagnosis , cure , mitigation , treatment , or prevention of disease in man or other animals ” are drugs . The FDA has not approved any drugs for the diagnosis , cure , mitigation , treatment , or prevention of COVID-19 in animals . The U.S. Department of Agriculture ’s ( USDA ) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service ( APHIS ) Center for Veterinary Biologics ( CVB ) regulates veterinary biologics , including vaccines , diagnostic kits , and other products of biological origin . Similarly , APHIS CVB has not licensed any products to treat or prevent COVID-19 in animals . \n  The FDA has taken action against fraudulent products intended to prevent or cure COVID-19 . The public can help safeguard human and animal health by reporting any products claiming to do so to 1 - 888-INFO - FDA ( 1 - 888 - 463 - 6332 ) .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. Are there any approved products that can prevent or treat COVID-19 in animals ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. No . Under the Federal Food , Drug , and Cosmetic ( FD&C ) Act , “ articles intended for use in the diagnosis , cure , mitigation , treatment , or prevention of disease in man or other animals ” are drugs . The FDA has not approved any drugs for the diagnosis , cure , mitigation , treatment , or prevention of COVID-19 in animals . The U.S. Department of Agriculture ’s ( USDA ) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service ( APHIS ) Center for Veterinary Biologics ( CVB ) regulates veterinary biologics , including vaccines , diagnostic kits , and other products of biological origin . Similarly , APHIS CVB has not licensed any products to treat or prevent COVID-19 in animals . \n The FDA has taken action against fraudulent products intended to prevent or cure COVID-19 . The public can help safeguard human and animal health by reporting any products claiming to do so to 1 - 888-INFO - FDA ( 1 - 888 - 463 - 6332 ) .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.4652421, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc66218-7085-11ea-9b40-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc662cc-7085-11ea-9a4f-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc662fe-7085-11ea-b953-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. Is it true that animals , like dogs , cats , and cattle , get their own types of coronavirus ?", "answerText": "A. Yes . Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses . Some coronaviruses cause cold - like illnesses in people , while others cause illness in certain types of animals , such as cattle , camels , and bats . Some coronaviruses , such as canine and feline coronaviruses , only infect animals and do not infect humans . For example , bovine coronavirus causes diarrhea in young calves , and pregnant cows are routinely vaccinated to help prevent infection in calves . This vaccine is only licensed for use in cattle for bovine coronavirus and is not licensed to prevent COVID-19 in cattle or other species , including humans . \n  Dogs can get a respiratory coronavirus , which is part of the complex of viruses and bacteria associated with canine infectious respiratory disease , commonly known as “ kennel cough . ” While this virus is highly contagious among both domestic and wild dogs , it is not transmitted to other animal species or humans . \n  Most strains of feline enteric coronavirus , a gastrointestinal form , are fought off by a cat ’s immune system without causing disease . However , in a small proportion of these cats , the virus can cause feline infectious peritonitis ( FIP ) , a disease that is almost always fatal . \n  Other species , like horses , turkeys , chickens , and swine , can contract their own species - specific strains of coronavirus but , like the other strains mentioned above , they are not known to be transmissible to humans . More information is available in AVMA ’s fact sheet about coronaviruses in domestic species .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. Is it true that animals , like dogs , cats , and cattle , get their own types of coronavirus ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. Yes . Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses . Some coronaviruses cause cold - like illnesses in people , while others cause illness in certain types of animals , such as cattle , camels , and bats . Some coronaviruses , such as canine and feline coronaviruses , only infect animals and do not infect humans . For example , bovine coronavirus causes diarrhea in young calves , and pregnant cows are routinely vaccinated to help prevent infection in calves . This vaccine is only licensed for use in cattle for bovine coronavirus and is not licensed to prevent COVID-19 in cattle or other species , including humans . \n Dogs can get a respiratory coronavirus , which is part of the complex of viruses and bacteria associated with canine infectious respiratory disease , commonly known as “ kennel cough . ” While this virus is highly contagious among both domestic and wild dogs , it is not transmitted to other animal species or humans . \n Most strains of feline enteric coronavirus , a gastrointestinal form , are fought off by a cat ’s immune system without causing disease . However , in a small proportion of these cats , the virus can cause feline infectious peritonitis ( FIP ) , a disease that is almost always fatal . \n Other species , like horses , turkeys , chickens , and swine , can contract their own species - specific strains of coronavirus but , like the other strains mentioned above , they are not known to be transmissible to humans . More information is available in AVMA ’s fact sheet about coronaviruses in domestic species .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465274, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc6634c-7085-11ea-9591-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc66376-7085-11ea-9062-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc663a8-7085-11ea-a81e-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. If my pet previously had a species - specific coronavirus , does that make them more or less likely to get COVID-19 ?", "answerText": "A. To date , there have been no reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 . \n  There is no data to suggest that current or previous infection with another strain of coronavirus would make your pet more or less likely to get COVID-19 .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. If my pet previously had a species - specific coronavirus , does that make them more or less likely to get COVID-19 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. To date , there have been no reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19 . \n There is no data to suggest that current or previous infection with another strain of coronavirus would make your pet more or less likely to get COVID-19 .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465292, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc66402-7085-11ea-b595-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc6645c-7085-11ea-9d3d-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc664ac-7085-11ea-ae13-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. If my pet has been vaccinated for species - specific coronavirus , does that make them more or less likely to get COVID-19 ?", "answerText": "A. Species - specific coronavirus vaccines are unlikely to work against this type of coronavirus because it is a new virus that is different from the species - specific strains of coronavirus targeted by the vaccine .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. If my pet has been vaccinated for species - specific coronavirus , does that make them more or less likely to get COVID-19 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. Species - specific coronavirus vaccines are unlikely to work against this type of coronavirus because it is a new virus that is different from the species - specific strains of coronavirus targeted by the vaccine .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465318, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc66506-7085-11ea-add5-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc66562-7085-11ea-ac4c-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc665a6-7085-11ea-a2a3-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. My pet has health problems and goes to the vet regularly for treatment . Should I be doing anything different to manage their health during the COVID-19 outbreak ?", "answerText": "A. While you should not avoid necessary visits to your veterinarian due to the COVID-19 outbreak , you should exercise reasonable caution just like you would if you were going to any other public place . If you are concerned about your own health or that of your pet when going to the veterinarian , contact their office in advance to discuss any recommended precautions .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. My pet has health problems and goes to the vet regularly for treatment . Should I be doing anything different to manage their health during the COVID-19 outbreak ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. While you should not avoid necessary visits to your veterinarian due to the COVID-19 outbreak , you should exercise reasonable caution just like you would if you were going to any other public place . If you are concerned about your own health or that of your pet when going to the veterinarian , contact their office in advance to discuss any recommended precautions .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465345, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc6661e-7085-11ea-a75e-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc6666e-7085-11ea-ad60-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc666be-7085-11ea-9707-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. Are there going to be any animal drug shortages due to the COVID-19 outbreak ?", "answerText": "A. The FDA has been and is continuing to closely monitor the supply chain with the expectation that the COVID-19 outbreak may impact the animal medical product supply chain . \n  We have been reaching out to manufacturers as part of our approach to identifying potential disruptions or shortages . We will use all available tools to react swiftly to help mitigate the impact if a potential disruption or shortage is identified . \n  Learn more on our Animal Drug Shortage Information page .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. Are there going to be any animal drug shortages due to the COVID-19 outbreak ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. The FDA has been and is continuing to closely monitor the supply chain with the expectation that the COVID-19 outbreak may impact the animal medical product supply chain . \n We have been reaching out to manufacturers as part of our approach to identifying potential disruptions or shortages . We will use all available tools to react swiftly to help mitigate the impact if a potential disruption or shortage is identified . \n Learn more on our Animal Drug Shortage Information page .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465374, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc6674a-7085-11ea-bf65-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc667b8-7085-11ea-ad6f-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc66808-7085-11ea-b101-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. Is it true that veterinarians ca n’t get supplies like surgical gowns , gloves and masks ?", "answerText": "A. Because COVID-19 is spreading rapidly from person to person , availability of personal protective equipment ( PPE ) for human healthcare professionals exposed to COVID-19 cases is critical . The FDA is aware that as the COVID-19 outbreak continues to expand globally , the supply chain for these devices will continue to be stressed as demand exceeds available supplies . The FDA has received information from healthcare organizations that some distributors may have placed certain types of PPE on allocation , basing the quantity available to the healthcare organization on previous usage , not projected use . Increased use may exceed the available supply of PPE , resulting in shortages at some healthcare organizations . \n  The FDA recommends conservation strategies for use by healthcare organizations and personnel — categorized for a range of clinical needs and supply levels — intended to assist healthcare organizations in determining conservation procedures during this time . The FDA ’s recommendations are intended to augment , and not intended to replace , specific controls and procedures developed by health care organizations , CDC , or CDC ’s Healthcare Infection Control Practices Advisory Committee ( HICPAC ) to aid in infection prevention and control . \n  The FDA is collaborating with manufacturers of surgical masks and gowns to better understand the current supply chain issues related to the COVID-19 outbreak , and to avoid any widespread shortages of these products . \n  The FDA will continue to keep healthcare providers , manufacturers , and the public informed if new or additional information becomes available .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. Is it true that veterinarians ca n’t get supplies like surgical gowns , gloves and masks ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. Because COVID-19 is spreading rapidly from person to person , availability of personal protective equipment ( PPE ) for human healthcare professionals exposed to COVID-19 cases is critical . The FDA is aware that as the COVID-19 outbreak continues to expand globally , the supply chain for these devices will continue to be stressed as demand exceeds available supplies . The FDA has received information from healthcare organizations that some distributors may have placed certain types of PPE on allocation , basing the quantity available to the healthcare organization on previous usage , not projected use . Increased use may exceed the available supply of PPE , resulting in shortages at some healthcare organizations . \n The FDA recommends conservation strategies for use by healthcare organizations and personnel — categorized for a range of clinical needs and supply levels — intended to assist healthcare organizations in determining conservation procedures during this time . The FDA ’s recommendations are intended to augment , and not intended to replace , specific controls and procedures developed by health care organizations , CDC , or CDC ’s Healthcare Infection Control Practices Advisory Committee ( HICPAC ) to aid in infection prevention and control . \n The FDA is collaborating with manufacturers of surgical masks and gowns to better understand the current supply chain issues related to the COVID-19 outbreak , and to avoid any widespread shortages of these products . \n The FDA will continue to keep healthcare providers , manufacturers , and the public informed if new or additional information becomes available .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.fda.gov/emergency-preparedness-and-response/mcm-issues/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-frequently-asked-questions", "sourceName": "FDA", "dateScraped": 1585352973.465408, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9bc6689e-7085-11ea-b1df-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9bc668f8-7085-11ea-a2f5-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9bc66948-7085-11ea-bd98-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Q. What is FDA ’s GFI # 269 - Enforcement Policy Regarding Federal Veterinary - Client - Patient Relationship ( VCPR ) Requirements to Facilitate Veterinary Telemedicine During the COVID-19 Outbreak ?", "answerText": "A. On March 24 , 2020 , the FDA issued this guidance to facilitate veterinarians ’ ability to provide veterinary telemedicine services during the COVID-19 pandemic .  \n  The agency intends to temporarily suspend enforcement of portions of the federal veterinarian - client - patient relationship ( VCPR ) requirements relevant to certain FDA regulations . The VCPR is the professional relationship between the veterinarian , client ( e.g. , animal owner or caretaker ) , and the animal patient(s ) . The federal VCPR definition requires that veterinarians physically examine animal patients and/or make medically appropriate and timely visits to the location where the animals are kept . Therefore , the federal VCPR definition can not be met solely through telemedicine . \n  To help veterinarians utilize telemedicine to address animal health needs during the COVID-19 pandemic , FDA does not intend to enforce the animal examination and premises visit portion of the VCPR requirements relevant to FDA regulations governing Extralabel Drug Use in Animals and Veterinary Feed Directive ( VFD ) drugs . This will allow veterinarians to prescribe drugs in an extralabel manner or authorize the use of VFD drugs without direct examination of or making visits to their patients , which will limit person - to - person interaction and the potential spread of COVID-19 in the community . \n  Given the temporary nature of this policy , the FDA plans to reassess it periodically and revise or withdraw this guidance as necessary .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Q. What is FDA ’s GFI # 269 - Enforcement Policy Regarding Federal Veterinary - Client - Patient Relationship ( VCPR ) Requirements to Facilitate Veterinary Telemedicine During the COVID-19 Outbreak ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "A. On March 24 , 2020 , the FDA issued this guidance to facilitate veterinarians ’ ability to provide veterinary telemedicine services during the COVID-19 pandemic .  \n The agency intends to temporarily suspend enforcement of portions of the federal veterinarian - client - patient relationship ( VCPR ) requirements relevant to certain FDA regulations . The VCPR is the professional relationship between the veterinarian , client ( e.g. , animal owner or caretaker ) , and the animal patient(s ) . The federal VCPR definition requires that veterinarians physically examine animal patients and/or make medically appropriate and timely visits to the location where the animals are kept . Therefore , the federal VCPR definition can not be met solely through telemedicine . \n To help veterinarians utilize telemedicine to address animal health needs during the COVID-19 pandemic , FDA does not intend to enforce the animal examination and premises visit portion of the VCPR requirements relevant to FDA regulations governing Extralabel Drug Use in Animals and Veterinary Feed Directive ( VFD ) drugs . This will allow veterinarians to prescribe drugs in an extralabel manner or authorize the use of VFD drugs without direct examination of or making visits to their patients , which will limit person - to - person interaction and the potential spread of COVID-19 in the community . \n Given the temporary nature of this policy , the FDA plans to reassess it periodically and revise or withdraw this guidance as necessary .", "answerLinks": {}}}
